Guide to the Donald Pippin Collection MUS.0003
Music Library
- Reviews, circa 1967-2011; 274 computer file(s) 274 TIF facsimiles
  - Vie Parisienne - Berkeley Voice, 1984 August 1; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
  - Vie Parisienne / Oh, boy! / Oh, Kay!, undated; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
    Drewes, Stephen; Gershwin, George; Kern, Jerome; Offenbach, Jacques, 1819-1880
  - Xerxes, undated; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
  - Xerxes, undated; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
  - Xerxes, undated; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
  - Xerxes - Peninsula Times-Tribune, 1982 March 22; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
    Handel, George Frideric, 1685-1759; Owen, Angela M.
  - Yanked from the harem - Contra Costa Times, 1987 April 21; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
    Milstein, Ronit; Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791
  - Yanked from the harem - San Francisco Chronicle, undated; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
    Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791; Tircuit, Heuwell
  - Yanked from the harem - Opera Guide, 1987 March 14; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
    Carr, R. T.; Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791
  - Yanked from the harem, 1997 February 28; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
    Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791; Rowe, Georgia
  - Yanked from the harem - San Francisco Chronicle, undated; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
  - Yanked from the harem - Voice, undated; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
  - Yanked from the harem - Opera Guide, 1989 March 28; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
    Lowens, Stephen; Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791
- Anthologies, 2005-2012; 3 computer file(s) 2 MS Word 97-2003 documents 1 PDF Document
  - As the lights go up ...: tales from the opera, 2005; 1 computer file(s) 1 MS Word 97-2003 document
    Summary
    This file contains many of Pippin's narrative introductions to acts of the many operas that the Pocket Opera Company has performed.
  - Pocketful of lyrics, 2012; 2 computer file(s) 1 MS Word 97-2003 document 1 PDF Document; The PDF document includes the title page, dedication, table of contents, and preface sections of this anthology, which are missing from the MS Word document. These additional sections have been scanned from a hard copy of the anthology. This has resulted in incorrect page numbering at the start of the document. The preface is numbered as pages 1-4. Page numbering then starts again at page 1 for the first chapter, Marriage of Figaro.
    Contents summary
    Alternate title: A world of lyrics. This file contains Pippin's English translations for arias from multiple operas along with texts for introductory and linking narrations and, in some cases, graphics of music notation for the first lines of the arias. At the end of the document is list of operas that Pippin has translated to English.
    Arias included are from the following operas: Marriage of Figaro/Mozart -- Don Giovanni/Mozart -- Cosi fan tutte (The way of women)/Mozart -- Abduction from the seraglio=Yanked from the harem/Mozart -- Magic flute/Mozart -- Barber of Seville/Rossini -- Cenerentola=Cinderella/Rossini -- Italian girl in Algeria/Rossini -- Count Ory/Rossini -- Elixir of love/Donizetti -- Don Pasquale/Donizetti -- Lucia di Lammermoor/Donizetti -- Lucrezia Borgia/Donizetti -- Macbeth/Verdi -- Rigoletto/Verdi -- Traviata/Verdi -- Falstaff/Verdi -- Halka/Moniuszko -- Haunted manor/Moniuszko -- Orpheus in the underworld/Offenbach -- Belle Helene/Offenbach -- Vie Parisienne/Offenbach -- Bandits/Offenbach -- Bridge of sighs: Carnival in Venice/Offenbach -- Perichole/Offenbach -- Princess of Trebizonde/Offenbach -- Bluebeard/Offenbach -- Tales of Hoffman/Offenbach -- Bartered bride/Smetana -- Two widows/Smetana -- Carmen/Bizet -- Eugene Onegin/Tchaikovsky -- Queen of Spades/Tchaikovsky -- Manon/Massenet -- Boheme/Puccini -- Madame Butterfly/Puccini -- Tosca/Puccini -- Manon Lescaut/Puccini -- Rondine=The swallow/Puccini -- Merry widow/Lehar -- Cunning little vixen/Janacek.
- Speeches, 1996; 1 computer file(s) 1 PDF document
  - Offenbach in four acts, 1996; 1 computer file(s) 1 PDF document
    Description
    A talk given at The Palace of the Legion of Honor, San Francisco, 1996.
- Tributes, 1985; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
  - Ode by one of your skylarks, 1985; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
    Dudley, Anna Carol
- Interviews, 1996 February 16; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
  - Pippin interview - Journal Français d'Amérique, 1996 February 16; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
    Benjamin, Sonia; Pippin, Donald
- Media Materials, 2013-07-07-2016-07-17; 20 computer file(s) (mp4)
  20 digital files of operatic performances: 1. Merry wives of Windsor / Otto Nicolai -- 2. Pocket Opera gala (02-23-2014) -- 3. The magic flute / Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart -- 4. Eugene Onegin / Peter Ilich Tchaikovsky -- 5. Agrippina / George Frideric Handel -- 6. The pearl fishers / Georges Bizet -- 7. The merry widow / Franz Lehár -- 8. Don Pasquale / Gaetano Donizetti -- 9. Alcina / George Frideric Handel -- 10. I pagliacci / Ruggiero Leoncavallo -- 11. My fair Galatea / Franz von Suppé -- 12. Cosi fan tutte / Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart -- 13. Pocket Opera gala (01-24-2016) -- 14. Martha / Friedrich von Flotow -- 15. King for a day / Giuseppe Verdi -- 16. Giulio Cesare / George Frideric Handel -- 17. I pagliacci / Ruggiero Leoncavallo -- 18. My fair Galatea / Franz von Suppé -- 19. Rigoletto / Giuseppe Verdi -- 20. La vie parisienne / Jacques Offenbach.
  Operas
  - Merry wives of Windsor by Otto Nicolai; English version by Donald Pippin, 2013-07-07; 2 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Performance by Pocket Opera. Complete opera performed at the Hillside Country Club, Berkeley, CA, Sunday, July 7, 2013; Nicolas Aliaga, director.
    Operas; Nicolai, Otto, 1810-1849
  - Pocket Opera Gala, [produced by] Donald Pippin, 2014-02-23; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Pocket Opera Gala performance at Forest Hill Clubhouse, February 23, 2014. Performers include Jordan Eldredge, Gabrielle Guidi, Robert Vann, Daniel Yoder, Marcelle Drankers, and Andrew NickellSelinske.
    Operas -- Excerpts; Pippin, Donald, 1925-
  - The Magic Flute by [Wolfgang Amadeus] Mozart; [English version by] Donald Pippin, 2014-03-09; 2 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Performance by Pocket Operaof complete opera at the Legion of Honor [San Francisco], on March 9, 2014; Nicolas Aliaga, director.
    Operas; Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791
  - Eugene Onegin by Piotr Ilyich Tchaikovsky; [English version by] Donald Pippin, 2014-04-06; 2 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Performance by Pocket Opera at the Hillside Country Club, Berkeley, CA, April 6, 2014; Andrew Morgan, director.
    Operas; Tchaikovsky, Peter Ilich, 1840-1893
  - Agrippina by G.F. Handel, 2014-04-27; 2 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Performance by Pocket Opera, at the Legion of Honor [San Francisco], April 27, 2014.
  - Pearl fishers by [Georges] Bizet; [English version by Donald Pippin], 2014-06-08; 2 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Performance by Pocket Opera, at the Legion of Honor [San Francisco], June 8, 2014; Nicolas Aliaga, director.
    Operas; Bizet, Georges, 1838-1875
  - Merry widow by Franz Lehar; [English version by Donald Pippin], 2014-07-13; 2 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Performance by Pocket Opera, at the Legion of Honor [San Francisco], July 13, 2014; Nicolas Aliaga, director.
    Operas; Lehár, Franz, 1870-1948
  - Don Pasquale by Donizetti; [English version by] Donald Pippin, 2015-01-17; 2 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Performance by Pocket Opera, at the Legion of Honor [San Francisco], January 17, 2015; Nicolas Aliaga, director.
    Operas; Donizetti, Gaetano, 1797-1848
  - Alcina by [George Frederic] Handel; [English version by] Donald Pippin, 2015-04-26; 2 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Concert performance by Pocket Opera, at the Legion of Honor, April 26, 2015.
    Operas; Handel, George Frideric, 1685-1759
  - I pagliacci by Leoncavallo; [English version by Donald Pippin]. My fair Galatea by Franz von Suppé; [English version by Donald Pippin], bulk; 2 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Performance of I pagliacci by Pocket Opera, at the Legion of Honor, May 31, 2015. Performance of My fair Galatea, at Hillside Country Club, Berkeley, CA, June 7, 2015. The second work was directed by Nicolas Aliaga.
    Operas; Suppé, Franz von, 1819-1895; Leoncavallo, Ruggiero, 1858-1919
  - Così fan tutte by [Wolfgang Amadeus] Mozart; [English version by] Donald Pippin, 2015-07-12; 2 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Performance by Pocket Opera, at the Legion on Honor [San Francisco], July 12, 2015; Nicolas Aliaga, director.
  - Pocket Opera Gala: honoring Donald Pippin, 2016-01-24; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Gala prformance at the San Francisco Opera House, on January 24, 2016. Performers include Marcelle Dronkers, Jennifer Ashworth, Tani Mandzy-Inala, Robert Vann, Nick Volkert, and Michael Mendelsohn.
  - Martha by Friedrich von Flotow; [English version by] Donald Pippin, 2016-02-28; 2 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Performance by Pocket Opera, at Hillside Country Club, Berkeley, CA, February 28, 2016; Nicolas Aliaga, director.
    Operas; Flotow, Friedrich von, 1812-1883
  - King for a day by [Giuseppe] Verdi; [English version by] Donald Pippin, 2016-04-10; 2 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Performance by Pocket Opera, at Hillside Country Club, Berkeley, CA, April 10, 2016; Jane Hammett, director.
    Operas; Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901
  - Giulio Cesare by George Frideric Handel; [English version by] Donald Pippin., 2016-04-24; 2 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Performance by Pocket Opera, at the Legion of Honor, April 24, 2016.
  - I pagliacci by Leoncavallo; [English version by Donald Pippin]. My fair Galatea by Franz von Suppé; [English version by] Donald Pippin, 2016-05-15; 2 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Performance by Pocket Opera, at Hillside Country Club, Berkeley, CA, May 15, 2016.
    Operas; Leoncavallo, Ruggiero, 1858-1919; Suppé, Franz von, 1819-1895
  - Rigoletto [by Giuseppe Verdi]; [English version by] Donald Pippin, 2016-06-12; 2 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Performance by Pocket Opera, at the Legion of Honor [San Francisco], June 12, 2016; Igor Vieira, director; David Drummond, music director.
  - La vie parisienne by Offenbach; [English version by] Donald Pippin, 2016-07-17; 2 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Performance by Pocket Opera, at the Legion of Honor [San Francisco], July 17, 2016; Nicolas Aliaga, director.
    Operas; Offenbach, Jacques, 1819-1880